Guide to the New York State Association of Family and Consumer Science Educators records, 1975-2015.
New York State Association of Family and Consumer Science Educators records, 1975-2015.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State Association of Family and Consumer Science Educators records, 1975-2015.
4955
New York State Association of Family and Consumer Science Educators.
15.2 cubic feet
Reports, slides, texts, photographs, exams, newsletters, notebook.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Curriculum material, including annual reports of the Association, slides and photographs, texts, old Regents examinations, newsletters, a President's Notebook, meeting minutes.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Formerly known as the New York State Home Economics Teachers Association (HETA). This association was conceived in 1961, chartered in 1969, and changed its name in December 1999.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Curriculum material, including annual reports of the Association, slides and photographs, texts, old Regents examinations, newsletters, a President's Notebook, meeting minutes.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State Association of Family and Consumer Science Educators.; New York State Home Economics Teachers Association.
Subjects:
Home economics--Study and teaching--New York (State).
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Newsletters.; Slides (photographs).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST (incomplete)
- New York State Association of Family and Consumer Science Educators Records
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 1962-1978 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Annual Business Meeting Minutes, 1979-1984 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1962-1968 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1969-1971 (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1972-1976 (Box 14, Folder 7-9)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1976-1978- (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1978-1980 (Box 14, Folder 12-13)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 14-16)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1982-1984 (Box 14, Folder 17-19)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1984-1986 (Box 14, Folder 20-23)
  - Agendas, Minutes, Flyers, 1990-1992 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Reports, 1990-1992 (Box 14, Folder 25-26)
  - Financial Reports, 1990-1992 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Testimony and Marketing, 1990-1992 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Awards, Board Members, 1990-1992 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - In-Service Leaders, 1990-1992 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - State Education Dept., 1990-1992 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - State Education Department Publications: Action: Image and Positive Change and News Capsule, 1990-1992 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Conferences, 1990-1991 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Planning papers for the first joint conference of NYSAEHE, NYSHEA and NYSHETA, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Gavel bag and a textbook from New York City, 1942-1943 (Box 16)
  - Historical Files, 1969-1990 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Teacher's Association Executive Board Meeting Agendas, 1982-2004 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Ruth Ritter Memorial Scholarship, 1981-1998 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Ruth Ritter and Ruth Ann Schultz Memorial Scholarships, 2000-2010 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Teacher Association Newsletters, Past Actions, Financial Status, Letters, 1978-1998 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Application forms, Constitutions, Treasurer's Reports, Membership Lists, 1989-1994 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - New York State Teacher of the Year, 2001-2010 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - New York State Teacher of the Year, 1994-2000 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - New York State Teacher of the Year, 1982-1993 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Promising New Professionals, 2004-2010 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Distinguished Service Award and Other Awards, 1996-2010 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Responding to Change - Lake Placid Conference, 1991-1993 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Programs of Work, 1990-1992 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Strategic Guide Book, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Historian's Report, 2015 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - United FCS Conference, 2014 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - President's Notebook, July - October 1998 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - President's Notebook, November 1998 - February 1999 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - President's Notebook, March - April 1999 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - President's Notebook, May - June 1999 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - President's Notebook, July - August 1999 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - President's Notebook, September 1999 (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
  - President's Notebook, November 1999 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - President's Notebook, December 1999 - January 2000 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Presdient's Notebook, February 2000 (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
  - President's Notebook, March - April 2000 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - President's Notebook, May - June 2000 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - NATFACS Notebook, 1999-2000 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - New York State Home Economics Teachers Association (NYSHETA) Business Meeting, August 1988 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - NYSHETA - Board Meeting Minutes and Memos, 1989-1993 (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
  - NYSHETA - Executive Board Meeting, October 1988 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - NYSHETA - Executive Board Meeting, February 1989 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - NYSHETA - Executive Board Meeting, August 1989 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - NYSHETA - Executive Board Meeting, May 1989 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - NYSHETA - Executive Board Meeting, February 1990 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - NYSHETA - Executive Board Meeting, June 1990 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - NYSHETA Board Meeting Minutes, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - NYSHETA Board Meeting Minutes, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 23-24)
  - NYSHETA Board Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - NYSHETA Board Meeting Minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - NYSHETA Board Meeting Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - NYSHETA Board Meeting Minutes, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - NYSHETA Board Meeting Minutes, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - NYSHETA Board Meeting Minutes, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - New York State Association of Family and Consumer Science Educators (NYSAFCSE) Board Meeting Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - NYSAFCSE Correspondence, 1999-2002 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 2001-2002 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 2003-16 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 2004 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - NYSAFCSE Board Meeting Minutes, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - NYSAFCSE State Awards Program, 2008 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Membership Lists, 2000-2002 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Newsletter-"Ultimate E-News", Fall 2009-May 2011 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Newsletter-"Ultimate E-News", 2011-09-2014-01 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Newsletter-"Get the FACS", 2009-11-2011-05 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Newsletter-"Get the Facts", 2011-09-2014-06 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Newsletter-"News Capsule", Fall 2009-Fall 2010 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Newsletter-"News Capsule", 2007 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    published in Winter
  - Newsletter-"News Capsule", 2011 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    published in Fall and Winter
  - Photographs, 1930-1999 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, 1980-1989 (Box 19, Folder 2)